export default data14 = [
    {
        id: "q1",
        question: "Which film produced in the UK was one of the most commercially successful films of all time and one of the highest-grossing film franchises?",
        options: ["Harry Potter", "Spider-man", "The Lord of the Rings", "Indiana Jones"],
        correct_option: "Harry Potter"
    },
     {
        id: "q2",
        question: "When did the first farmers come to Britain?",
        options: ["10,000 years ago", "6,000 years ago", "15,000 years ago", "2,000 years ago"],
        correct_option: "6,000 years ago"
    },
     {
        id: "q3",
        question: "Can court orders be obtained to protect a person from being forced into a marriage?",
        options: ["Yes", "No"],
        correct_option: "Yes"
    },
     {
        id: "q4",
        question: "What medal did Mary Peters win in the 1972 Olympics?",
        options: ["She did not win any medals", "Silver", "Gold", "Bronze"],
        correct_option: "Gold"
    },
     {
        id: "q5",
        question: "What was invented by Alan Turing in the 1930s?",
        options: ["The jet engine", "The television", "The Turing machine", "The ball pen"],
        correct_option: "The Turing machine"
    },
     {
        id: "q6",
        question: "Which of the following tells us about how people lived in England just after the Norman Conquest?",
        options: ["The Domesday Book", "The Book of Common Prayer", "The Canterbury Tales", "The Carta Magna"],
        correct_option: "The Domesday Book"
    },
     {
        id: "q7",
        question: "Who led a team of scientists to ‘split the atom’ for the first time?",
        options: ["Alexander Fleming", "Alan Turing", "Ernest Rutherford", "Sir Peter Mansfield"],
        correct_option: "Ernest Rutherford"
    },
     {
        id: "q8",
        question: "What song is sung by people in the UK and other countries when they are celebrating the New Year?",
        options: ["Auld Lang Syne", "he British Anthem", "Jingle Bells", "White Christmas"],
        correct_option: "Auld Lang Syne"
    },
     {
        id: "q9",
        question: "What was the religion of the Puritans?",
        options: ["Hindu", "Catholic", "Sikh", "Protestant"],
        correct_option: "Protestant"
    },
     {
        id: "q10",
        question: "What is the name of Irish people who favoured complete independence from the UK in the 19th century?",
        options: ["Fenians", "Quakers", "Highlanders", "Suffragettes"],
        correct_option: "Fenians"
    },
     {
        id: "q11",
        question: "What is the minimum age required to drive a motorcycle?",
        options: ["16 years old", "17 years old", "18 years old", "21 years old"],
        correct_option: "17 years old"
    },
     {
        id: "q12",
        question: "The members of the House of Lords, known as peers, are elected by the people.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correct_option: "False"
    },
     {
        id: "q13",
        question: "When did the Emancipation Act abolish slavery throughout the British Empire?",
        options: ["1835", "1823", "1807", "1833"],
        correct_option: "1833"
    },
     {
        id: "q14",
        question: "Who is responsible for crime, policing and immigration?",
        options: ["The Chancellor of the Exchequer", "The Foreign Secretary", "The Speaker", "The Home Secretary"],
        correct_option: "The Home Secretary"
    },
     {
        id: "q15",
        question: "What kind of genre was the film Wallace and Gromit created by Nick Park?",
        options: ["A soap opera", "A silent movie", "An animated film", "An action film"],
        correct_option: "An animated film"
    },
     {
        id: "q16",
        question: "Anyone who is violent towards their partner – whether they are a man or a woman, married or living together – can be prosecuted.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correct_option: "True"
    },
     {
        id: "q17",
        question: "An additional rented piece of land where people can grow fruit and vegetables is known as:",
        options: ["Parcel", "Garden", "Terrain", "Allotment"],
        correct_option: "Allotment"
    },
     {
        id: "q18",
        question: "What is the name of the battle where the Scottish led by Robert the Bruce defeated the English in 1314?",
        options: ["The Battle of Agincourt", "The Battle of Bannockburn", "The Battle of Trafalgar", "The Battle of Waterloo"],
        correct_option: "The Battle of Bannockburn"
    },
     {
        id: "q19",
        question: "Who took the English throne after the death of Henry VIII?",
        options: ["Elizabeth I", "Edward VI", "Queen Mary", "James I"],
        correct_option: "Edward VI"
    },
     {
        id: "q20",
        question: "Carrying a weapon is a criminal offence, unless it is for self-defence:",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correct_option: "False"
    },
     {
        id: "q21",
        question: "Prohibition of thought, conscience and religion is one of the principles included in the European Convention of Human Rights:",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correct_option: "False"
    },
     {
        id: "q22",
        question: "Which of the following words comes from the Viking language?",
        options: ["Table", "Scunthorpe", "Pencil", "Rabbit"],
        correct_option: "Scunthorpe"
    },
     {
        id: "q23",
        question: "What is the name of the highest mountain in Wales?",
        options: ["Lake District", "Snowdon", "South Downs", "Giant’s Causeway"],
        correct_option: "Snowdon"
    },
     {
        id: "q24",
        question: "Where did the Vikings come from?",
        options: ["France and Germany", "Sweden and Finland", "Denmark and Norway", "Sweden and Germany"],
        correct_option: "Denmark and Norway"
    },
    
]